listorious.com 2018-11-06

# Privacy Policy

The Muck Rack services, including (without limitation) all websites, mobile applications and other interactive properties through which the service is delivered (collectively, the “Service”) are owned, operated and distributed by Muck Rack, LLC, a Delaware limited liability company (referred to in this Privacy Policy as “Muck Rack” or “we” and through similar words such as “us,” “our,” etc.). This Privacy Policy outlines the personal data that Muck Rack may collect, how Muck Rack uses and safeguards that data, and with whom we may share it. This Privacy Policy is intended to provide notice to individuals regarding personal data in an effort to be compliant with the data privacy laws and regulations of the jurisdictions in which Muck Rack operates. 

Muck Rack encourages our customers, visitors, business associates, and other interested parties to read this Privacy Policy, which applies to all users, including users who are simply viewing content available via the Service, users who have subscribed for the Services, are contributors of data and/or content via the Service. By using our website or submitting personal data to Muck Rack by any other means, you acknowledge that you understand and agree to be bound by this Privacy Policy, and agree that Muck Rack may collect, process, transfer, use and disclose your personal data as described in this Statement. Further, by accessing any part of the service, you are agreeing to THE TERMS AND CONDITIONS OF OUR TERMS OF SERVICE (the “TERMS OF SERVICE”). **If you do not agree to any of these terms, YOU SHOULD not use the Service.**

##  What Personal Data Does Muck Rack Collect? 

During your use of the Service or through other communications with Muck Rack, personal data may be collected and processed by Muck Rack. You may affirmatively provide us with certain personal data (such as your name, employer, email address, phone number, mailing address, credit card information, email receipt and open data etc.) when participating in various activities on the Service. 

##  What Non-Personal Data Does Muck Rack Collect? 

By using the Service, Muck Rack may collect certain non-personal data: 

  * **Information Collected by “Cookies”:** When you access the Service, we may send one or more “cookies” to your computer. A “cookie” is a small line of text that is stored with your browser, which we use to help provide better service to you. Your browser has options to accept, reject or provide you with notice when a cookie is sent. We may use cookies for many purposes, including (without limitation) to save your password so you don’t have to re-enter it each time you visit the Service, and to deliver content (which may include third party advertisements) specific to your interests. 
  * **Log File Information:** Our servers automatically record certain information that your browser sends whenever you access the Service. These server logs may include information such as your web request, Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, browser type, browser language, referring / exit pages and URLs, platform type, number of clicks, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed and the order of those pages, the amount of time spent on particular pages, the date and time of your request, and one or more cookies that may uniquely identify your browser. 

##  How Does Muck Rack Use Personal Data and Non-Personal Data? 

Any personal information that you voluntarily disclose online (in messages and chat areas, within your public profile page, through a User Submission, etc.) becomes publicly available and can be collected and used by others. 

If you have not opted out from receiving marketing communications from us, we may use your email address, phone number or other personal data to send commercial or marketing messages. We also may use your email address, phone number and other personal data for non-marketing or administrative purposes (such as notifying you of major Service changes or for customer service purposes). You cannot opt out of receiving communications for non-marketing or administrative purposes without discontinuing your use of the service. 

With regard to non-personal data, we use aggregated information (such as anonymous user usage data, cookies, IP addresses, browser type, clickstream data, etc.) to improve the quality and design of the Service and to create new features, promotions, functionality, and services by storing, tracking, and analyzing user preferences and trends. In addition, we may use "cookies," clear gifs and log file information to deliver content (which may include third party advertisements) specific to your interests, and remember information so that you will not have to re-enter it each time you visit the Service. 

##  Will Muck Rack Share Personal Data with Others? 

We will not share your personal data with other, third-party companies for their commercial or marketing use without your consent or except as part of a specific program or feature for which you have the ability to opt-in or opt-out. 

We may provide personal data to Muck Rack employees, consultants, affiliates or other businesses or persons for the purpose of processing such information on our behalf. In such circumstances, we require that these parties agree to protect the confidentiality of such information and to comply in all respects with this Privacy Policy. 

We may share non-personal data (such as anonymous User usage data, referring / exit pages and URLs, platform types, number of clicks, etc.) with interested third-parties to assist them in understanding the usage patterns for certain content, services, advertisements, promotions, and/or functionality on the Service. 

In addition, we may release personal data: (i) to the extent we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with any applicable law, enforce any provision of the Terms of Service, protect ourselves against any liability, defend ourselves against any claims, protect the rights, property and personal safety of any user or protect the public welfare; or (ii) to respond to a court order, subpoena, or search warrant. 

##  International Data Transfer 

For individuals in Switzerland and the European Union (EU), please note that Muck Rack is a US based company. If you use the Service, all information, including personal information, will be transferred to Muck Rack (including third parties to which data was disclosed as described above) in the United States and any information made public via our website may be viewed by individuals located anywhere in the world. Although this may include recipients of information located in countries where there may be a lower level of legal protection for your personal data than in your country, we will protect your information in accordance with requirements applicable to the law in your particular jurisdiction. By using the Service, you unambiguously consent to the transfer of your personal information and other information to the United States and elsewhere for the purposes and uses described herein. 

##  EU Data Privacy Rights 

If you are located in the EU, the General Data Protection Regulation grants you certain rights under the law. In particular, the right to access, correct, or delete the personal data Muck Rack holds about you. Muck Rack will retain your data for the length of time you engage with Muck Rack’s services until you request deletion of such personal data. 

Upon request, Muck Rack will grant individuals reasonable access to personal data that it holds about them. In addition, Muck Rack will take reasonable steps to permit individuals to correct, amend, or delete information it holds about them. Muck Rack also relies upon each individual to assist in providing accurate updates of his or her personal data. In order to access, correct, amend, or delete the personal data Muck Rack holds about an individual, the individual should contact [privacy@muckrack.com](mailto:privacy@muckrack.com). 

If you have a comment, question, or complaint about how Muck Rack is handling your personal data, we hope that you contact us at [privacy@muckrack.com](mailto:privacy@muckrack.com) in order to allow us to resolve the matter. In addition, individuals located in the EU may submit a complaint regarding the processing of their personal data to the EU data protection authorities (DPAs). The following link may assist you in finding the appropriate DPA: <https://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/bodies/authorities/index_en.htm>

##  Publication of Data 

Muck Rack publishes data and information on its website based on two concepts. First, Muck Rack believes that publication of this data is in the public interest, and, therefore, we exercise the right to freedom of expression in order to fulfill this public interest. Further, the information compiled here was obtained from the public domain, or it can be assumed that the nature of the information is such that publication does not expose any individual to unjustified harm. Second, Muck Rack publishes data and information based on its legitimate interest to provide the Service, and by providing the Service, no unwarranted harm is caused to any individual and the nature of the published information is such that the interests of the individual do not outweigh Muck Rack’s legitimate interest. That said, if a individual has questions or concerns about the information made available through Muck Rack, we encourage you to contact us at [privacy@muckrack.com](mailto:privacy@muckrack.com). 

##  Third Party Advertisers 

We may allow other companies, called third-party ad servers or ad networks, to serve advertisements within the Service. These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to send, directly to your browser, the advertisements and links that appear on the Service. They automatically receive your IP address when this happens. They may also use other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons) to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and to personalize the advertising content you see. You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers or ad networks for more information on their practices and for instructions on how to opt-out of certain practices. This Privacy Policy does not apply to them, and we cannot control their activities. 

##  Is My Information Secure? 

We have implemented security measures to protect personal data collected on the Service against loss, misuse or alteration. In addition, your account information is protected by a password for your privacy and security. It is important that you protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer by logging off once you have finished using a shared computer. Moreover, despite the precautions described above, we cannot and do not guarantee that the individual user information you have transmitted will not be intercepted by others and/or decrypted or accidentally disclosed, and we accept no liability for any unintentional disclosure. 

##  In the Event of Merger, Sale, or Bankruptcy 

In the event that we are acquired by or merged with a third party entity, Muck Rack reserves the right to transfer or assign the information we have collected from users as part of such merger, acquisition, sale, or other change of control. In the unlikely event of our bankruptcy, insolvency, reorganization, receivership, or assignment for the benefit of creditors, or the application of laws or equitable principles affecting creditors’ rights generally, we may not be able to control how your personal information is treated, transferred, or used. 

##  Children’s Privacy 

You must be at least 13 years old to register to use the Service. 

##  Changes to this Privacy Policy 

Muck Rack reserves the right to modify this Privacy Policy from time to time in order that it accurately reflects the regulatory environment and our data collection principles. When material changes are made to this Privacy Policy, Muck Rack will post the revised Statement on our website. This Privacy Policy was last modified as of May 2018. 

##  California Privacy Rights 

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits users of the Service who are California residents to request certain information regarding its disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an e-mail with “California Privacy Rights” in the heading to [privacy@muckrack.com](mailto:privacy@muckrack.com) or write us at: 

Muck Rack Privacy Rights  
588 Broadway #503  
New York, New York 10012 

##  Contact Us 

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy or the services provided by Muck Rack, please contact us at: [privacy@muckrack.com](mailto:privacy@muckrack.com)
